# **Shubham Mishra**

# Data Engineer

☑ shubham.mishra@gmail.com 📞 9876543210 in LinkedIn 🕡 Github

Bengalore Karnataka

#### **Profile**

3+ years of experience in various projects related to Data Modeling, Data Analysis, Design, and Development for Data warehousing environments. Practical understanding of Data modeling concepts like Start-Schema Modeling. Snowflake Schema Modeling, Fact and Dimension tables. Comprehensive knowledge and experience in process improvement, normalization/de-normalization, data extraction, data cleansing, and data manipulation. Exceptional troubleshooting skills with ETL technologies.

# **Professional Experience**

05/2020 - present Bangalore, India

**Data Engineer** 

Wipro

Salesforce to Redshift Ingestion - Migration from Informatica to Native AWS

Tech Stack - Salesforce, Informatica, S3, Lambda, Glue, AppFlow, Redshift, SNS

- Crafted generic scalable Native AWS solution for Salesforce to Redshift ingestion
- It helped to move ingestion pipelines from third-party tool Informatica and saved cost for the heavy license fee
- This generic framework helped other business units for smooth ingestion of newly onboarded Salesforce objects into a Redshift Data lake

#### **Dehleez - Report Scheduling Tool**

Tech Stack - Python, JavaScript, Django, Azkaban, Docker, Hive, Ajax, Bootstrap, **REST API, DataDog** 

- Enhanced Paytm's proprietary report scheduling tool which is used by business users working on data analysis where they can schedule their reports by writing HIVE/MySQL/Cassandra queries and report output in various formats
- Diff Checker Admins can check the difference between queries before approving reports
- Time slot picker to schedule a report The user can see scheduled reports for the next 4 hours from the intended schedule time and can pick the slot accordingly
- Dump report output into the S3 bucket The user can take a dump of report output into the AWS S3 bucket
- Cassandra Connector User can schedule reports having Cassandra query panels in addition to HIVE/MySQL

01/2019 – 05/2020 Mumbai, India

#### **Data Engineer**

Capgemini

Länsförsäkringar, or literally County Insurance, is a Swedish group of customer-owned insurance companies. The group consists of 23 independent companies, one in each of the counties of Sweden (pre-1998 division), that cooperate under a common brand name.

## Role: SQL and SSIS Developer & SQL Support

- Troubleshoot live bugs and resolved them on production.
- To fulfill the requirement of altering existing objects.
- Performance tuning using system views & Execution Plan.
- Highly involved in development activities as per requirement from client
- Taking ownership of technical issues, and Handling issues
- Proper documentation on development and Issues handled providing the Root cause of the problem.

#### **Skills**

### **Programing Language:**

Python, Java Scala, C++, and Linux Scripting

#### **Databases**

MySQL, Elastic Search, Cassandra, HBase, Hive, SQL Server

#### **Dashboarding & Monitoring Tools**

Grafana, Kibana, Power BI

#### **AWS Services**

S3 bucket, EMR, Lambda, Cloudwatch, DynamoDB, Redshift, MWAA, Glue, SNS, SQS

### **Code Management and Documentation**

Git, BitBucket, Azure Develops, Circle CI, Travis CI

### **Web Development Framework**

Django, Flask

#### **Distributed Framework**

Hadoop, Spark, Kafka, BigQuery

#### **Workflow Management**

Airflow, IBM Tivoli

## **Build Tools & Containers**

Docker, Kubernetes

#### **Education**

06/2015 – 06/2018 Master of Computer Applications

Prayagraj, India National Institute of Technology Allahabad (MNNIT), U.P

06/2012 – 06/2015 Bachelor in Computer Science

Mumbai, India Mumbai University

# **Certificates**

AWS certified Database specialty

 AWS certified Solution Architect • Azure Data Scientist

Azure Fundamental